Fawzi Al-Jasim System Administrator



Rational System Administrator with 19 years of experience enhancing operations for organizations through information systems solutions.

Proven track record of transforming specifc business goals related to growth and efciency improvements into new system designs.

Knowledgeable innovator known for recommending new technologies to enhance existing systems and introduce new systems.

I am MTA certifed from Microsoft and ITIL foundation certifed.
20 years' experience in media production,
Working on 2D Animation and both of video and photo editing.

Eastern Province, Al-Ahsa, Saudi Arabia



fawzinj@hotmail.com



+966503005893



https://www.linkedin.com/in/fawzi-aljassim-581b9a

Experience

Aug 2007 – Feb 2022 Dammam, Saudi Arabia

System Administrator

Ball United Arab can

- Planned computer systems using information engineering and structured analysis.
- Presented business leaders with ROI estimations to drive project planning.
- Developed diagrams to describe and lay out logical operational steps.
- Installed system updates to address vulnerabilities and reduce security issues.
- Enhanced interfaces to promote better functionality for users.
- Assessed business requirements to create focused solutions.
- Organized system operating procedures to strengthen controls.
- Provided recommendations regarding new hardware and software to keep IT infrastructure up to date.
- Investigated system issues and implemented resolutions to reduce downtime.
- Provided backup and assistance for administration of physical and virtual server infrastructure and storage area networks.
- Reviewed technical work of consultants and third-party support providers.
- Administered and maintained anti-virus and anti-malware software on end-user computing devices.
- Assisted in troubleshooting network, cybersecurity and non-standard software and hardware related issues.
- Supported end-user networks in Microsoft environment incorporating Microsoft Server and Workstation practices.
- Formatted documents using Microsoft products follow specific corporate style guides.
- Installed and configured server and workstation hardware, OS and custom applications.
- Implemented Microsoft Active Directory to mitigate security risks and bolster access management.
- Microsoft AD, Group Policy, DNS and DHCB
- Microsoft Failover & cluster

- Microsoft Hyper-V virtualization solution with redundant
- Microsoft NIC Teaming for Windows server 2012R2
- Microsoft Exchange Server 2010 installation and configuration
- Working on Microsoft ISA 2006
- Microsoft WSUS update server 3.0,3.2 and 6.2
- Microsoft Imaging
- HP & Dell Servers
- HP SAN Storage
- HP LTO3 and LTO5 Tap Drive
- Xerox Multifunction Machine
- Y-Soft center print controller software
- Configure WAN network
- Configure LAN & Wan Internet
- Network cabling
- Fortinet200 firewall
- Ubiquiti Unifi network solution
- Symantec Backup exec for backup system
- Symantec Endpoint protection Antivirus
- Adobe creative suite

Mar 2007 – Jul 2007 Khobar, Saudi Arabia

Computer Engineering

Arabic Computer System

- Imaged and prepared new computers for integration into company networks and systems.
- Corrected connectivity faults to restore user access to local networks, cloud-based storage and public web.
- Performed troubleshooting and repaired peripheral devices such as printers, scanners.
- Monitored systems in operation and quickly troubleshot errors.
- Set up PCs, projectors and microphones for use in video conferencing rooms.
- Managed system-wide operating system and software deployments as well as related software upgrade problems.
- Performed troubleshooting to correct computer hardware and software malfunctions.
- Used diagnostic tools to identify hardware failures and replace non-functional components.
- Linked computers to network and peripheral equipment.
- Working on Remedy.

- Microsoft Office.
- Adobe applications (Acrobat, Photoshop & Illustrator).
- Windows OS & Mac OS.
- Relocate PC, Scanner & Printer.
- Repartition hard disk without losing data or OS, Prepare the partitions of hard disk (Mac, Windows or Linux), Change from Linux OS back to Windows OS & Backup users' data from HDD to HDD or throw network.
- Creating Image for Operating System or for hard disk.

Jul 2003 – Jun 2007 Dammam, Saudi Arabia

Computer Engineering

Jeraisy Computer Services Est

- Imaged and prepared new computers for integration into company networks and systems.
- Corrected connectivity faults to restore user access to local networks, cloud-based storage and public web.
- Performed troubleshooting and repaired peripheral devices such as printers, scanners.
- Monitored systems in operation and quickly troubleshot errors.
- Set up PCs, projectors and microphones for use in video conferencing rooms.
- Managed system-wide operating system and software deployments as well as related software upgrade problems.
- Performed troubleshooting to correct computer hardware and software malfunctions.
- Used diagnostic tools to identify hardware failures and replace non-functional components.
- Linked computers to network and peripheral equipment.
- Working on Remedy.
- Microsoft Office.
- Adobe applications (Acrobat, Photoshop & Illustrator).
- Windows OS & Mac OS.
- Relocate PC, Scanner & Printer.
- Repartition hard disk without losing data or OS, Prepare the partitions of hard disk (Mac, Windows or Linux), Change from Linux OS back to Windows OS & Backup users' data from HDD to HDD or throw network.

 Creating Image for Operating System or for hard disk.

Education

Feb 2001 – Feb 2003 Alahsa, Saudi Arabia

Diploma, Computer Technology

Technical College

Skills

- System Architecture
- Performance Optimization
- IT Performance Report Creation
- Information security
- System Validation Design
- Technical Analysis
- Problem-Solving
- Planning and Coordination
- Teamwork and Collaboration
- Complaint resolution
- Staff education and training
- Creative problem solving
- Account management
- Technical Support
- Order fulfillment
- Administrative support
- Microsoft Exchange
- Microsoft PowerPoint
- Microsoft Word
- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft Outlook
- Microsoft Office
- Microsoft Windows
- Microsoft Windows Server
- Microsoft Active Directory
- Microsoft Group Policy
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe After Effects
- Graphics and animation
- 2D Animation
- Animation and motion graphics

Languages

- Arabic Native
- English Advanced

Projects

- Work in infostructure implementation
- I have done many 2D Animation with motion graphic with graphic design, also I have created some Ads for some company located in bot KSA & UAE.
- I also have some personal project for social media

Certifications

- Project Management Foundations (PMI & NASBA) Jul 2022
- Microsoft Technology Associate May 2019
- ITIL Foundation Certificate Jan 2017
- Managing and maintaining a Microsoft Windows Server – Jan 2005
- Excellence Institute for Languages Certificate May 2003
- Microsoft certification professional May 2002

Accomplishments

- Always introduce free solution keep saving for the corporation.
- Documented and resolved issue which led to results.
- Keep upgrading my knowledge of IT